I don't see anything at all,Sheldon.
我啥都没看见 Sheldon
Well,you're the doctor, but I am
constantly hearing this annoying sound.
得 你是医生 可我咋老耳鸣呢
Me,too.
我也是
Is it a high-frequency whistle?
是高频口哨音?
No,it's more of a relentless,
narcissistic drone.
不 比较像是无情而又自恋的嗡嗡声
Yup,there's no
inflammation at all,Sheldon.
嗯 根本没发炎 Sheldon
Then it must be a tumor.
那我肯定长瘤了
Seriously doubt it.
严重怀疑
Maybe it's a lingering bacterial infection
from all those childhood toilet swirlies.
可能是你孩提时代的那些卷纸
残留的细菌给感染了
Is that possible?
这有可能吗?
I used to get those all the time.
我以前常这么干
Even in church.
甚至在教堂都是
Well,if it is from a swirly,
there something I can do.
呃 要真是卷纸引起的
我倒是有办法对付
Okay,circle, circle,dot,dot,
now you have a cootie shot!
好咧 圈 圈 点 点
这是给你的虱子预防针!
- I'm going to bed.
- Okay,I'll be right in.
- 我要上床了
- 好 我马上就来
It's not enough that she mocks me,but that isn't
even the correct procedure for a cootie shot.
她藐视我还不算
虱子预防针根本就不是这么打的
Do you understand that Stephanie's not
here to treat your imaginary ailments?
Stephanie可不是来这儿治疗
你想象中的微恙的 明白?
How is it imaginary that I keep
hearing an octave above Middle C?
怎么可能是想象出来的?
不然我怎么老听见比中音C高八度的音?
Is that imaginary?
那是想象出来的?
I don't think so.
我可不这么认为
- Good night.
- Another thing.
- 晚安
- Leonard 还有件事
Under Article One,Section
Three of our Roommate Agreement,
基于我们室友协议的第一章第三节
I'm calling an emergency meeting.
我要求召开紧急会议
No,you're not.
才不呢
Leonard moves the meeting
not occur. Is there a second?
Leonard请求取消会议 还有别人吗?
None heard,the motion fails.
没有 请求驳回
I'd like to begin the meeting by congratulating you on
the progress in your relationship with Dr. Stephanie.
会议一开始 我想要祝贺你
同Stephanie医生的关系突飞猛进
Thank you.
谢了
That being said, we have to discuss the
implementation of the agreed upon "cohabitation" rider
说完客套话 我们得讨论一下
是否执行"同居"附加条款之内容
which has been activated now that
the two of you are living together.
在你俩住在一起之后
该条款正式生效了
We're not living together.
我俩没住在一起
I beg to disagree.
恕难同意
"A girlfriend shall be deemed
quote living with un-quote Leonard
"当某女子在此屋内待过以下时间
即可认为其与Leonard
when she has stayed over
for A:ten consecutive nights,
引号 同居 引号
A: 连续十个晚上
or B: more than nine nights
in a three week period,
或者B: 连续三周内超过九个晚上
or C: all the weekends of a
given month plus three weeknights.
或者C: 一个自然月中
每个周末外加三个晚上
That's absurd.
真是荒谬
You initialed it. See? L.H.,L.H.,L.H.
你签了字的 瞧? L.H. L.H. L.H.
(Leonard Hofstadter)
Wait,I only initialed it because
I never thought it would happen!
等等 我签字
是因为压根没想过这种事会发生
I initialed another clause naming you
my sidekick in case I get superpowers.
我还签了另一个条款说
一旦我拥有超能力就喊你死党来着
Hmm,yes,you did.
哼 没错 是你干的
Now,to review,the following
provisions are hereby activated:
现在总结陈词
以下条款也已激活生效:
In the refrigerator, as opposed to us having
two separate shelves and one communal shelf,
首先是冰箱里 本来我俩一人一个架子
这个架子是公用的
the three of us now get individual
shelves and the door becomes communal.
现在我们仨各拥有一个独立架子
冰箱门成为公用部分
Next,apartment vacuuming shall be
increased from two to three times a week
接着 每周的吸尘工作
由两次增加至三次
to accommodate the increased
accumulation of dead skin cells.
以适应新增的死皮细胞
Third,the bhroom schedule.
第三 洗手间的时间表
Now,I'm given to understand women have
different needs,so, we'll have to discuss that.
既然我已明了 女性需求不同
我们就得一起商量一下
I'm going to bed.
我要上床了
At least take this with you.
至少把这个带上
Look,and have Stephanie
initial here,here,here,here...
瞧 让Stephanie在这几个地方都签字
and... here.
还有... 这儿
This states that she does not now nor does she
intend to play a percussive or brass instrument.
这条规定她现在和将来都不能
弹奏打击乐器或铜管乐器
Sure sounds like a tumor
pressing on the auditory nerve.
听上去就是个瘤~
在挤压我的听觉神经~~
荣誉出品
翻译: 饭特稀 王泳东 布鲁瓶
校对: 欧屁屁
时间轴: 咔肉肉
No,absolutely not.
不 绝对不行
It's not a big deal.
We have latex gloves.
又没啥了不起的 我们有橡胶手套
I don't care what the symptoms are, my girlfriend
is not going to give you a prostate exam.
我不管你有何种症状
我女朋友才不会给你检查前列腺
Hi,Sheldon.
嗨 Sheldon
Good morning, Dr. Stephanie.
早上好 Stephanie医生
I ust Leonard satisfied
you sexually last night.
我相信Leonard昨晚让你爽歪歪了
Sheldon,we don't ask
questions like that.
Sheldon 地球人不会问这种问题
I heard you ask it over and over.
我听见你一遍又一遍地问来着
How is it inappropriate
for me to ask it once?
让我问一次有啥不恰当的?
He did very nicely.
他干得很棒
See? She's not offended.
瞧见没? 又没冒犯人家
And now you finally have an answer.
还让你小子知道了答案
Out of coffee. Need coffee.
咖啡没了 来借咖啡
Oh,hello.
噢 你好
Stephanie,right?
是Stephanie 对吧?
And-And-
And you are?
你-你-你是?
Penny,I live across the hall.
Penny 我住在走廊那头
I've heard a lot about you.
我常听他们提起你来着
Really?
真的吗?
I haven't heard a thing about you.
关于你 他可啥都没跟我提起呢
Leonard?
Why haven't I heard a thing about
this woman who lives across the hall
为啥你对于这个住在走廊那头的
好邻居只字不提呢?
and comes into your
apartment in the morning...
她可会大清早来你们屋
in her underwear?
还只穿着睡衣哟?
She's heard about you because
we're,you know, involved
我们跟她提起你来
是因为我和你...在谈朋友嘛
and you haven't heard
about her because...
我没同你提起她来是因为...
I never slept with her,I swear!
我从没同她睡过 我发誓!
In Leonard's defense,it
wasn't for lack of trying.
Leonard可是争辩说
自己想方设法要同她睡来着
Thank you,Sheldon.
谢谢侬 Sheldon
You're welcome,Leonard.
表客气 Leonard
Look,I'm just saying,um...
听着 我是说...
Penny is one of our many neighbors,you
know, and in our building,
Penny不过是我们众邻居之一
在我们这栋楼里
neighbors come and go,it's
very casual,no dress code.
邻里们串门是很正常的
也没什么着装要求
In fact,some mornings I'll just mosey
down to the third floor in my pajamas
实际上 在某些早晨
我会穿着睡衣跑去三楼
and have cereal with Mrs.Vartabedian.
同Vartabedian太太喝燕麦呢
Really? I have never once been invited
to have cereal with Mrs. Vartabedian.
真的假的? 她咋从来也不请我去喝?
She doesn't like you.
她不喜欢你
You have a gall bladder to remove
and I have to get in the shower
你得去给人动胆囊手术
我得进去洗澡
and Penny has clothes to put on,so...
而Penny要回房穿衣服 那么...
Well,it was very nice meeting you.
幸会幸会
Nice to finally meet you,too.
最终能见着你 我也很高兴
- And I'll see you
tonight? - Okay,bye-bye.
- 今晚见?
- 好咧 拜拜
What could I possibly have
done to offend Mrs. Vartabedian?
我做了啥对不起Vartabedian太太的事儿了?
So,that's Stephanie,huh?
她就是你的Stephanie?
Why do I feel like I'm the one
that just got the prostate exam?
为啥我觉得自己像才去查过前列腺的?
You know,she seems very nice.
她看起来相当不错嘛
Oh,she is. She's terrific.
那是 她好极了
And she's proving to
be a valuable roommate.
事实证明她是位珍贵的室友
Roommate? You guys are living together?
室友? 你们同居啦?
Like hippies.
很前卫吧
We're not living together.
我们没同居啦
Do I have to pull out
the paperwork again?
又要我拿出书面证明吗?
We're not living together.
我们没同居
Are you sure?
你确定?
How could I not be sure?
我怎么不能确定了?
Well,let's find out.
咱来检查下吧
Don't you think if a woman was living with
me I'd be the first one to know about it?
难道你不觉得 如果我和人同居了
我会是第一个知道?
Oh,sweetie,you'd be the
last one to know about it.
小伙子 你肯定是最后一个觉悟的
Hmm,cute dresses.
很漂亮的衣衣呀
I bet this looks great on you!
我打赌你穿这个一定靓!
We're not living together.
我们没同居
Okay,hmm...
好 嗯...
Scented candles, fuzzy
slippers, Floral bed sheets?
香蜡烛 毛拖鞋 印花床单?
We're not living together.
我们没同居
Okay,moving on.
那好 继续检查
Now,who are these guys at Disney World?
那 迪斯尼乐园里的这些家伙是谁哦?
Uh,the big dog is Goofy,
大狗是高飞
but the older couple with
the mouse ears,I have no idea.
但是有老鼠耳朵的那一对
我就不知道了
We're not living together!
我们没同居!
You're going to go down swinging,huh?
不见棺材不落泪?
All right,well,we got your body lotion,
好吧 我们发现了你的润肤露
your InStyle Magazine,your jewelry box.
你的InStyle时尚杂志 你的首饰盒
We're
not--
我们没--
Where's my Bat Signal?
我的蝙蝠侠标记哪去了?
You have a Bat Signal?
你有蝙蝠侠标记?
I did.
有呀
It was right here.
就放这儿的
She
must've--
她一定--
Oh,my God,we're living together.
噢 天啦 我们同居了
Really? What was your first clue?
真的? 你咋发现的?
New pants?
新裤子?
Yeah,Stephanie got them for me.
对 Stephanie给我买的
Nice. Cotton?
不错 全棉的?
Actually,I think it's more
of a wool,fire ant blend.
其实 我觉得更像是羊毛和热蚂蚁混纺
So,the girlfriend's
buying clothes for you,huh?
女友开始给你买衣服了?
- Sounds serious.
- It is actually.
- 来真的了
- 确实是
In fact,I gave it a lot of thought and I
decided it was time for us to live together.
事实上 我考虑了很久
我觉得是时候同居了
Oh,Leonard,huge mistake.
Leonard 亏大了你
There's a whole buffet of women out there
and you're just standing in the corner
外面那么多秀色可餐 唾手可得
你却站在角落
eating the same deviled
egg over and over again.
反复咀嚼你的芥末蛋
At least I have an
egg. What do you have?
起码我有蛋吃 你有啥?
A veritable smorgasbord of
potential sexual partners.
一大桌性感时髦靓妞儿大杂烩
等我去嘿咻呢
See the blonde over there?
瞧见那个金发妞了吗?
I can hit on her and you can't.
我可以去跟她搭讪 你却不能
So,go hit on her.
那 你去呀
She's not my type.
不是我的茶
Too bad,'cause she was
checking you out before.
太可惜了 她刚才还在看你咧
- She was?
- Of course not. Look at her.
- 真哒?
- 假的 你也不瞧瞧人家
I don't care what you guys think.
我不管你们怎么看的
Stephanie and I are very
happy living together.
Stephanie和我的同居生活很快乐
I will give either of you 20
dollars,right now to trade pants with me.
你们谁和我换裤子 我给他20刀
Sheldon,what are you doing here?
Sheldon 你在这儿干嘛?
Hang on.
稍等
130 over 80.
(血压)130/80
A little high.
有点高
We can attribute that to the stress
of sneaking past the security desk.
应该是偷偷溜过保安的桌子时
太紧张引起的
Where did you get the stethoscope
and the blood pressure cuff?
你在哪儿搞到听诊器和血压袖带的?
My aunt Marion gave them
to me for my 12th birthday.
Marion姑妈送我的12岁礼物
She thought if I failed at theoretical physics
that I should have a trade to fall back on.
她觉得要是我理论物理学没出路了
还可以有个谋生的出路
And by the way,the blood pressure
cuff is called a sphygmomanometer.
顺便提醒下 血压袖带叫血压计
I know.
谢谢提醒
Didn't they teach you
that in medical school?
难道医学院里不教这个?
- I'm busy here,Sheldon.
- I understand.
- 我很忙的 Sheldon
- 我知道
All I need is for you
to authorize these tests.
我只需要你授权这些检查
A cardiac stress test,a full body MRI,an
electromyogram,a CBC,baseline glucose.
心脏负荷测试 全身核磁共振
肌动电流图 全血球计数 葡萄糖基线测试
Upper GI?
上消化道造影?
Oh,and an exploratory laparoscopy.
还有腹腔镜探测检查
Last time I had hiccups,it felt like my
diaphragm was just going through the motions.
上次我打嗝 感觉我的隔膜也跟着动了
Go home,Sheldon.
回家吧 Sheldon
Can I at least have the upper GI?
至少来个上消化道造影?
I already drank the barium!
我已经喝了钡餐了!
Oh,good. Do you have
any fabric softener?
哦 太好了 你有织物软化剂吗?
Yeah,sure.
有 有
What are you washing? A crocodile?
你在洗什么? 洗鳄鱼皮呀?
No,the pants that Stephanie got me.
不 是Stephanie送我的裤子
Oh,sweetie,you can't machine
wash these. They'll be ruined.
小伙子 这个不能机洗 会洗坏的
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
- 确定吗?
- 当然
Oh,no. I wish you'd told me that sooner.
糟糕咧 你咋不早点告诉我呢
Are you guys having problems?
你俩怎么了?
No,everything's fine.
没事 一切顺利
Really?
真的?
Yeah,it's wonderful.
对呀 好极了
Okay,maybe this whole living together happened
kind of suddenly,but it's fine,it's great.
好吧 也许同居的事有点突然
但还好 很不错的
Okay,Leonard,honey,you know,if you're
uncomfortable with the way things are going,
Leonard 如果你不满意
恋爱关系的发展现状
you're allowed to say something.
你应该说出来
Are you sure? That doesn't sound right.
说真的吗? 听起来不太对
Believe me,your feelings are
just as important as hers.
相信我 你的感觉和她的一样重要
No,that doesn't sound right either.
不对 这个听着也不太对
Just tell her you need the relationship to move
at a pace that you both are comfortable with.
就告诉她 你需要这段关系
能兼顾你们两个的节奏
Yeah,I could say
something like that to her.
对 我可以给她那么说的
I'll go do that.
我去给她说说
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- 谢谢你
- 没什么
You ve a really good grasp on this.
谈这些东西你很拿手吧?
Maybe you could talk to her?
也许你可以帮我去说说?
You're kidding,right?
你开玩笑吧?
No,but that's okay.
没 也没关系啦
I'll go talk to her.
我去和她谈
Want to come with?
一起来吗?
Go!
快去!
- Oh,no.
- Whaa?
- 呀 不是吧
- 啥?
You were right. ur larynx
is terribly inflamed.
你说得对 你的喉咙红肿的厉害呀
I mean,I've never seen anything like it.
我都还没见过这么严重的
I knew it!
我就知道!
What do I do?
我该怎么办?
You're going to need to
stop talking immediately.
你得马上停止说话
- For how--
- Dut-dut-dut.
- 多久才...
- 得 得 得
Immediately.
马上
- Oh,hi,honey.
- Sheldon.
- 噢 嗨 宝贝
- Sheldon
What's going on?
他怎么了?
I just performed a "Sheldonectomy."
我刚做完"Sheldon切除术"
Careful,if you don't get it
all,it'll only come back woe.
小心哦 要是没斩草除根
只会后患无穷
Gotcha.
明白
Listen,we need to talk.
听着 我们得谈谈
Do we need to talk or
"do we need to talk"?
是"我们谈谈哈"
还是"我们得好好谈谈了"?
I don't know what that means.
不知道你什么意思
Okay,why don't you just tell me
what it is you have to tell me?
这样吧 你干脆直接把想说的告诉我吧
Okay,um,well,look,it's just that...
那好 呃 其实 你看 就是...
things between you and me
have been going pretty quick.
我们之间进展得着实快了点
And...
然后呢...
It's just a little scary.
有点吓人哇
Well,yeah,but scary good,right?
是啊 但这吓人也是好事 对吧?
Sure...
那当然...
When is scary not good?
吓人还有不好的咩?
But...
不过...
okay,um,I have feelings,right?
好吧 我心有所想 是不?
Okay,and it's perfectly okay
to express those feelings,right?
那好 把我所想的表达出来
也无可厚非 是不?
Of course,honey,why don't you
tell me what it is you're feeling?
当然了 宝贝 告诉我你在想些啥吧
Okay,we,I ju...I think it's important
to remember that we move at a pace
好吧 我只是...觉得有必要记清楚
我们的关系 发展的步伐...
that is our
speed and--
是我们的速度 然后...
Oh,shoot,I had it!
噢 真是 刚记得好好的
Okay,how about this? How about
I tell you what I'm feeling?
那 这样如何? 让我来告诉你我在想什么
What's that?
你想什么?
Really? Right now?
当真? 现在?
Why not?
为啥不呢?
I just ate,aren't you
supposed to wait an hour?
我刚吃过饭呢 不该等上个把小时?
I think that's for swimming.
我想那是对游泳而言吧
Oh,okay.
噢 好吧
I just hope I don't get cramps.
希望不会抽筋就是了
- Oh,I put your clothes in the dryer.
- Thank you.
- 噢 我把你衣服放烘干机了
- 谢谢
- Your pants are ruined.
- Good.
- 你的裤子洗坏了
- 忒好了
So,how did the talk with Stephanie go?
和Stephanie谈得怎么样了?
Well,um,on one level,really,really well.
呃 某方面来说 非常 非常好
So,you told her you
wanted to slow things down?
那你告诉她了 你想放慢脚步咯?
Not specifically,but,uh,I did
tell her that I had feelings.
没很明确地说 但是 呃
我确实说了我有些想法
Good,good.
好嘛 很好
And then what?
然后咋了?
And then,uh,the subject
got changed somehow.
然后就 呃 话题不知不觉就变了
You had sex,didn't you?
你们上床了 是吧?
little bit.
上了一点点
- What?
- Nothing.
- 怎么了?
- 没什么
Okay,well,it sounds like
things are going to work out.
好啊 看来事情会进展得很顺利
Yeah,it's all good.
Everything's going to work out.
是啊 都好着呢
一切都会很顺利的
One way or another.
正反都顺利
God,come on,Leonard,You are entitled to try
and make things go the way you want them to.
天 拜托 Leonard
你有权让事情按你的想法走下去
- Really?
- Yes!
- 是吗?
- 是的!
You don't always have to go
along with what the woman wants.
你没必要总是迁就女人
- What?
- Nothing. Just...
- 怎么了?
- 没什么 只是...
rethinking my whole life.
重新审视我这一辈子
Okay,here's the thing.
好啦 是这样的
I'm afraid that if I ask her
to move out,she'll just dump me.
如果我叫她搬出去
我怕她会甩了我
Well,it's a chance you have to take.
这个嘛 你不得不冒这个险
I mean,look,if it's
meant to be,it'll be.
你看嘛 该来的 总归躲不掉
Very comforting.
真是受用
Okay,so what do I say to her?
那我该怎么跟她说呢?
I don't know.
我不知道
I mean,what have women said to you when
they wanted to slow a relationship down?
当女人想慢慢发展感情时
她们怎么跟你说的呀?
I really like you,but I want
to see how things go with Mark?
我是真的喜欢你
但是我想试试和Mark发展一下
Yeah,that'll slow it down.
没错 这样是会慢下来
I'm sorry,I totally inteupted
you. What we you sang?
不好意思 我彻底打断了你
你刚说啥来着?
Oh,right,yeah,um.
噢 是的 没错
So,Stephanie,hereththing.
那个 Stephanie 事情是这样的
I really like yo
我是真的喜欢你
Oh,God,here comes the speech.
娘啊 这番话又开始了
What speech?
什么话?
"I really like you but maybe we sh
spend a little less time together"
"我是真的喜欢你
但是也许我们该少聚一点"
"'cause I need mspace but
I'll call you on Tuesday
"因为我需要点个人空间
但是我周二会给你打电话的"
and then you never
call me so I call you,"
之后你便一直没打 所以我打给你了
but you don't call me back and then
when I run into you at the coffee shop,
但你又没给我回电
然后 当我在咖啡店撞见你时
you pretend like you've been
having problems with your voice mail
你假装说你的语音信箱出了毛病
and I know that you're lying,
我当然知道你是撒谎
but I pretend like I don't care
even though I'm dying inside!
但还是假装不在乎
尽管内心悲痛欲绝
No!
不!
No,no!
不 不是的!
I wasn't going to say any of that.
这些话我一句都不会讲的
I was just going to say...
我只想要说...
I really like you.
我是真的喜欢你
Oh,good!
噢 那就好!
'Cause I really like you,too.
因为我也是真的喜欢你
Terrific.
好极了
Nice sweater.
毛衣不错嘛
Yeah,Stephanie got it
for me. It's kind of fun.
是吧 Stephanie买给我的
还蛮好玩的
It's got a big bird on it,dude.
上面印的可是只大鸟啊 老兄
Yeah,yeah,that's the fun part.
是啊 笑点就在这里嘛
We're also getting new curtains
for my bedroom,and a dust ruffle,
我们还在我卧室换了新窗帘 新床裙
and a duvet,and I don't
even know what a duvet is,
还有羽绒被 我都不知道羽绒被是啥玩意
but I'm pretty sure if I
did I wouldn't want one,
但我很确定要真知道了
我就不想要了
but every time I talk
to her about moving out,
只是每次我说起要分开住
she cries and we have sex.
她就哭啊 然后咱就嘿咻一场
You're lucky. With me,it's
usually the other way around.
你很走运啊 要是我
通常会是相反的结果
You know,if you can't talk to
her,why don't you just text her?
要知道 你若不能对她直说
为啥不给她发短信呢?
Isn't that kind of cowardly?
那岂不是太没骨气了?
Oh,yeah. It's beyond contemptible.
噢 没错 简直是奇耻大辱
It's true,but on the other hand
you are wearing a bird sweater.
话虽如此 但想一想
你都穿了大鸟毛衣了
Sold.
就这么办
"I think it would be better for our
relationship if you moved back to your place."
"我想 如果你搬回自己那里
对我们的关系会更有好处"
There. It's done.
好了 发完了
Good for you.
为你高兴啊
Yeah,good for me.
对 为我高兴
I'll never have sex again.
我再也没的嘿咻了
Hmm,I was wrong. See ya.
哟 说错了 回见
Penny.
喷你
Sheldon?
I have an inflamed larynx.
我喉咙发炎了
Okay?
嗯哼?
We're out of herbal
tea. Do you have any?
我们的药草茶喝完哩
你这儿有米?
Okay,let me check.
好的 我去看看吧
Some hiney would be nice,too.
要有轰蜜就更好咧
Hiney?
轰蜜? (hiney)
Honey.
蜂蜜 (honey)
本论坛字幕仅翻译交流学习之用
禁止任何商业用途否则后果自负